Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine
and today we're talking
about office stuff,
things in your office.
That's right. We are
talking about secrets in the
office or maybe specific
little things that people
talk about behind
other people's back.
Okay, bad things then. So this
is an elementary level lesson.
Before we get going though, let's take
a look at a phrase in today's vocabulary
preview, vocabulary preview.
All right, so the phrase
for today is actually
the same as the title for
this lesson and
that's office gossip.
Okay, y'all know what an
office is. What is gossip? So
to gossip means to
talk about other people
secretly or behind their
backs or maybe talk about
other people's problems
or private things.
So oh my god, did you hear? John
is totally going to break up with her.
So you're talking about people?
Yeah, them knowing.
Right. So you're talking about
their private things,
their relationships, maybe
you're even maybe
criticizing them. That's right.
So office gossip is talking
about people in your
office without them knowing.
So saying bad things about them.
Right. So without
any more delay, why
don't we listen to this
dialogue for the first time?
Hey, Eric, have you heard? No? Go on,
tell me. What's the latest office gossip?
Well, you didn't hear this from me, but the
room it is. Paula is getting a promotion.
No way, but she's a terrible worker and
you can't trust her. She's so too faced.
You can't believe anything
she says. Hey guys, what do you
do whispering about?
Oh, hi Paula, how are you?
I've got some good news.
I'm getting a promotion.
Congratulations.
Eric and I would just
say that you were the best person
for the job. Yes, you're the best.
All right, we're back.
So we have four key
words that we want to look
at from this gossip dialogue.
So why don't we take a look at
those now in language takeaway?
Language takeaway. Okay,
the first word is rumor.
Now this is an interesting
word about gossip.
Yeah, a rumor. So a
rumor is a story that might
or might not be true. Right. Okay, so I
heard a rumor that they broke up yesterday.
Okay, so you're not sure if they broke
up or no one has told you for a fact.
No, it means I probably heard it from
someone else who heard it from someone else,
who heard it from someone
else who doesn't really know.
Right. So rumors are
maybe guesses about people.
And you don't
know if they're true.
You see, that's a lot with
famous people, movie stars.
They always talk about rumors that maybe
they got married in secret or something.
Exactly. There's a rumor that Angelina
Jolie and Brad Pitt are breaking up. Right.
Okay, so we don't think
that we don't know if it's true.
Okay, that's a rumor. So
now the rumor that they heard
was that this girl Paula
is getting a promotion.
Promotion, this is an
important office word.
This means to be offered a better job in
your company. That means to move up.
To move up, right. All
right, so this is a noun.
You get a promotion,
right? Yes, I got a promotion
last year, which also
meant I got more money.
Okay, awesome. So
that is a promotion.
Now, when they were talking
about the promotion, the
girl said, I can't believe
the guys and Eric said,
I can't believe she's
getting a promotion.
She's so too faced. Too
faced. So think about what this
means to have two faces,
to be too faced means
to have two different sides to your
personality, a good one and a bad one. Okay.
So like, um, I could be
very nice to Marco Marco.
Wow, you look so good
today. There's a nice guy.
She's a hard worker. And then,
oh my God, Marco's is an idiot.
He's like, never working.
And he's always on the
phone. Oh, hi, Marco.
That is too faced. That's very
good. All right. So too face means
to have two different
sides to your personality.
Now, it's interesting the
way that you use this word.
You say too faced,
right? So you have to
add the idiot in. You
can't say he is too face,
or he has too face. And
now it's an adjective.
So he's too faced.
Okay. Okay. Too faced.
I don't like people who are
too faced. Okay. Very good.
And we have one final
word. And it's actually
a verb when people talk
like this when they're talking.
Okay. So they're
talking widely, very
quietly to whisper. Okay. So
what are you whispering about?
Uh oh. So usually when people are whispering,
they're talking about a rumor, right?
Or they're talking in secret. You don't
want somebody else to hear you. Right.
So when you want to be very
quiet, like at the movie theater,
you whisper whisper.
Okay. So those are four
words for language
takeaway. When we go back,
listen to the dialogue
again. And we'll be
back to take a look
at a couple of phrases.
Hey, Eric, have you
heard? No, go on.
Tell me what's the latest
office gossip. Well, you didn't
hear this from me. But
the rumor is, Paula is
getting a promotion. No way. But she's
a terrible worker and you can't trust her.
She's so too faced. You
can't believe anything she says.
Hey, guys. What are you
two whispering about?
Oh, hi, Paula. How are you?
I've got some good news.
I'm getting a promotion.
Congratulations.
Eric and I were just saying
that you were the best
person for the job.
Yes, you're the best.
All right, we're back. So now
we have three key phrases
from this great dialogue
on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So this
first one is the beginning to
any great rumor. We say,
have you heard? All right.
So have you heard? Have you
heard that she got a promotion?
Right. You're not really asking.
Right. Although it is a
question. Have you heard?
But you're not really
expecting an answer.
What you're, this means I'm
going to tell you some gossip.
Right. Have you heard?
Because maybe I did,
maybe I didn't, but
I'm still going to say it.
She's still going
to say it. Right.
So usually you can say, uh,
what, right? Or in this case,
Eric goes, no, go on. Tell me
what's the latest office gossip.
So obviously, he knows
it's going to be gossip.
Right. Have you
heard? All right.
And so the next thing Pam says is,
well, you didn't hear this from me.
Okay. What does this mean?
This is typical. This is a way
of saying, okay, don't tell
anyone that I told you.
So you can tell people,
but just don't tell
them that I said that this
happened because Pam
doesn't want to get in trouble.
Right. She doesn't want
anyone to know that
she was giving out
rumors. So that's why she's
starting out with, well, you
didn't hear this from me.
But the rumor is, okay.
So you can, so this is a
way of saying, all right, don't
tell anyone that I told you.
You didn't hear this from me.
And also you can go, you
can say, but the rumor is, or you
can say, but rumor has
it. Now rumor has it that
Paula is getting a promotion.
So you can go both ways.
And now he exclaimed
something that's very strange.
If you just look at it
from these two words,
no way. No way. What is
no way? Well, in this context,
no way means really?
Wow. Right. I'm surprised.
So it's a way to
express surprise.
That's right. But be careful
because there's another
meaning to this phrase.
For example, Marco, could
you help me out and get
the groceries from the car?
No way. Huh? Okay. That
means no. Okay. Okay.
No way. That means
no, but also if you say it
like, no way, right? You're
saying, wow, that's so interesting.
So it can be an expression of
surprise, or it can be a way of
saying no, very firmly, no way.
Exactly. All right.
So three great phrases
there. Very interesting dialogue
about gossip, very common
in the office environment.
So why don't we listen to the dialogue
again? And we'll be back in a little bit.
Hey, Eric. Have you heard? Hmm? No. Go on.
Tell me. What's the latest office gossip?
Well, you didn't hear this from me, but
the room is. Paula is getting a promotion.
No way. But she's a terrible worker and
you can't trust her. She's so too faced.
You can't believe anything
she says. Hey, guys.
What are you two whispering
about? Oh, hi, Paula. How are you?
I've got some good news.
I'm getting a promotion.
Congratulations. Eric
and I were just saying
that you were the best person for the job.
Yes. You're the best.
Okay. We're back. So
office gossip is generally,
well, it's common. It
happens in every office,
but I think that it's
good to avoid too much
gossip because sometimes
people's feelings can get
hurt. Yeah. It's
actually very interesting
because usually the bigger
the company is, I think
more gossip starts to
spread because, you know,
they're departments. So you got the
marketing department, the finance department.
So you're like, oh, Kathy
from finance, she slept with a
Tom from marketing
and stuff like that.
Then you have the gossip
about bosses. Right. Did you see
totally left for the weekend?
But his wife was at home.
Yeah. And also one
of the situations where
all lot of rumors and
office gossip starts to
come up is office parties
or the office Christmas
parties where people maybe
are drinking or something
happens in a lot of
rumors start to spread.
And they're more relaxed
and usual than do things
they would normally
do. Absolutely.
So maybe we could open this up
to you. Is there a common rumor
or office gossip that
you hear in your office?
Or is there that one secretary or guy
that's always spreading rumors in gossiping?
And don't use any real
names. You can just tell us
general stories. But
that's about it for us here
today at EnglishPod.
Hope you've enjoyed this.
Check out our website,
EnglishPod.com. Let us know
if you have any questions or concerns.
But until next time, bye bye.